A Guide to the Copenhaver Store Records, 1911-1958
Special Collections, Kegley Library, Wytheville Community College
Special Collections, Kegley Library, Wytheville Community College
Copenhaver Store Records 2002.2
Special Collections, Kegley Library
2002.2
32 folders..
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gary and Ann Laing donated the Records to the Kegley Library in December 2002.
Historical Information
The Huddle and Copenhaver Company opened in 1911 under the partnership of Dr. J. M. Miller, Mac D. Copenhaver, and R. C. Huddle. John Copenhaver also was an partner. The store sold general merchandise as well as produce, hardware, furniture, building supplies, and other items. The store changed its name from Huddle and Copenhaver to M. D. Copenhaver Store. The produce business was known also as Crockett Produce Company and Independent Produce Shippers. The store provided sales and shipment of apples, cabbage, cattle, hogs, and other produce to southwest Virginia and beyond.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of 32 folders containing correspondence, ledgers, receipt books, check stubs, sales sheets, and inventory sheets.
Contents List
- Folder 1. Correspondence. Crockett Produce Company. 27 July - 7 August 1918., 20 items. (Box-folder 1:1)
- Folder 2. Correspondence. Crockett Produce Company. 8 August - 21 August 1918., 21 items. (Box-folder 1:2)
- Folder 3. Correspondence. Crockett Produce Company. 24 August - 1 October 1918., 17 items. (Box-folder 1:3)
- Folder 4. Huddle and Copenhaver Company. July 1918., 19 items. (Box-folder 1:4)
- Folder 5. Correspondence. Huddle and Copenhaver Company. 1 August - 3 August 1918., 21 items. (Box-folder 1:5)
- Folder 6. Huddle and Copenhaver Company. 6 August - 9 August 1918., 18 items. (Box-folder 1:6)
- Folder 7. Correspondence. Huddle and Copenhaver Company. 10 August - 14 August 1918., 20 items. (Box-folder 1:7)
- Folder 8. Correspondence. Huddle and Copenhaver Company. 15 August - 21 August 1918., 23 items. (Box-folder 1:8)
- Folder 9. Correspondence. Huddle and Copenhaver Company. 15 August - 21 August 1918., 22 items. (Box-folder 1:9)
- Folder 10. Correspondence. Huddle and Copenhaver Company. 2 September - 6 September 1918., 22 items. (Box-folder 1:10)
- Folder 11. Correspondence. Huddle and Copenhaver Company. 7 September - 9 September 1918., 26 items. (Box-folder 1:11)
- Folder 12. Correspondence. Huddle and Copenhaver Company. 10 September - 13 September 1918., 19 items. (Box-folder 1:12)
- Folder 13. Correspondence. Huddle and Copenhaver Company. 14 September - 19 September 1918., 20 items. (Box-folder 1:13)
- Folder 14. Correspondence. Huddle and Copenhaver Company. 21 September - 3 October 1918., 11 items. (Box-folder 1:14)
- Folder 15. Correspondence. Miscellaneous. 1920-1938, undated., 13 items. (Box-folder 1:15)
- Folder 16. Ledger. Huddle and Copenhaver Company. 1918., 164 p.; name index. (Box-folder 1:16)
  On flyleaf: "List of accounts and notes...taken from 1918 inv. to H & Co. are to be divided equally between R. C. Huddle and M. D. Copenhaver as collected." Ledger provides name of customer, amount, and date of payment to account.
- Folder 17. Ledger. Cabbage Shipments. 1923., [80 p.] (Box-folder 1:17)
  Ledger provides name of farmer, amount of cabbage shipped, name of railway car, and name of purchaser of cabbage.
- Folder 18. Ledgers. Livestock sales. 1930s., 2 items. (Box-folder 1:18)
  Ledgers provide name of farmer, date, number of livestock purchased, weight, and price.
- Folder 19. Ledgers. Livestock sales. 1930s, 1938-1957, 2 items. (Box-folder 1:19)
  Ledgers provide name of farmer, date, number of livestock purchase, weight and price.
- Folder 20. Inventory sheets. 1938-1946., 7 items. (Box-folder 1:20)
  Sheets dated: 31 December 1938; 31 December 1941; 31 December 1942; 1 January 1944 [1943 inventory]; 31 December 1944; 31 December 1945; 31 December 1946.
- Folder 31. Sales Sheets. Mac D. Copenhaver, M. D. Copenhaver and Son. 1924, 1952-1958., 23 sheets. (Box-folder 1:21)
  Sheets provide name of customer and amount of account.
- Folder 22. Receipt Book. Independent Produce Shippers, Inc. 1948-1949., 1 item. (Box-folder 1:22)
- Folder 23. Receipt Book. Independent Produce Shippers, Inc. 1949., 1 item. (Box-folder 1:23)
- Folder 24. Receipt Book. Independent Produce Shippers, Inc. 1949-1950., 1 item. (Box-folder 1:24)
- Folder 25. Receipt Book. Independent Produce Shippers, Inc. 1951-1952., 1 item. (Box-folder 1:25)
- Folder 26. Receipt Book. Independent Produce Shippers, Inc. 1952-1953., 1 item. (Box-folder 1:26)
- Folder 27. Receipt Book. Independent Produce Shippers, Inc. 1953-1956., 1 item (Box-folder 1:27)
- Folder 28. Expense Account Book. M. D. Copenhaver Store. 1957-1958., 1 item; [28 p.] (Box-folder 1:28)
- Folder 29. Sales Ledger. M. D. Copenhaver Store. 1947-1958., 1 item. (Box-folder 1:29)
  On cover board: "Dividends on notes, stock, and rent from two dwelling houses and post office."
- Folder 30. Check Stubs. M. D. Copenhaver Store. 1957., 1 item. (Box-folder 1:30)
- Folder 31. Check Stubs. M. D. Copenhaver Store. 1958., 1 item. (Box-folder 1:31)
- Folder 32. Receipt Book. Huddle and Copenhaver Store. 1911-1912., 1 item. (Box-folder 1:32)